Joseph Edward Davies Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Joseph Edward Davies Papers 1860-1958 1912-1958
MSS17855
Davies, Joseph Edward, 1876-1958
75,000 items
224 containers plus 5 oversize
97.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Diplomat, lawyer, and author. Correspondence, diaries, drafts of articles, books, and speeches, printed matter, and scrapbooks relating to Davies's career as an ambassador to Belgium and Russia, presidential advisor, and author.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965--Correspondence.; Beaverbrook, Max Aitken, Baron, 1879-1964--Correspondence.; Byrnes, James F. (James Francis), 1882-1972--Correspondence.; Byrnes, James F. (James Francis), 1882-1972.; Churchill, Winston, 1874-1965--Correspondence.; Churchill, Winston, 1874-1965.; Cummings, Homer S. (Homer Stillé), 1870-1956--Correspondence.; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948--Correspondence.; Davies, Joseph Edward.; Early, Stephen T. (Stephen Tyree), 1889-1951--Correspondence.; Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon, 1897-1977--Correspondence.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955--Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Correspondence.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965--Correspondence.; Grew, Joseph C. (Joseph Clark), 1880-1965--Correspondence.; Gromyko, Andreĭ Andreevich, 1909-1989--Correspondence.; Halifax, Edward Frederick Lindley Wood, Earl of, 1881-1959--Correspondence.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923--Correspondence.; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986--Correspondence.; Henderson, Loy W. (Loy Wesley), 1892-1986--Correspondence.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972--Correspondence.; Hopkins, Harry L. (Harry Lloyd), 1890-1946--Correspondence.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955--Correspondence.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952--Correspondence.; Krock, Arthur, 1886- --Correspondence.; Lange, Oskar, 1904-1965--Correspondence.; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967--Correspondence.; Lunt, Alfred--Correspondence.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959--Correspondence.; McIntyre, Marvin Hunter, 1878-1943--Correspondence.; Molotov, Vyacheslav Mikhaylovich, 1890-1986--Correspondence.; Morgenthau, Henry, 1891-1967--Correspondence.; Murrow, Edward R.--Correspondence.; Novikov, N. V. (Nikolaĭ Vasilévich), 1903- --Correspondence.; Pearson, Drew, 1897-1969--Correspondence.; Pittman, Key, 1872-1940--Correspondence.; Rayburn, Sam, 1882-1961--Correspondence.; Rickenbacker, Eddie, 1890-1973--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Rosenman, Samuel I. (Samuel Irving), 1896-1973--Correspondence.; Stalin, Joseph, 1878-1953.; Stettinius, Edward R., Jr. (Edward Reilly), 1900-1949--Correspondence.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965--Correspondence.; Trujillo Molina, Rafael Leónidas, 1891-1961--Correspondence.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972--Correspondence.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tydings, Millard E. (Millard Evelyn), 1890-1961--Correspondence.; Vinson, Fred M., 1890-1953--Correspondence.; Vyshinsky, Andrey Yanuaryevich, 1883-1954--Correspondence.; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965--Correspondence.; Warner, Harry Morris, 1881-1958--Correspondence.; Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961--Correspondence.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944--Correspondence.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924--Correspondence.; Windsor, Edward, Duke of, 1894-1972--Correspondence.
Organizations
Potsdam Conference (1945: Potsdam, Germany); Sea Cloud (Yacht); United States. Federal Trade Commission.; United States. President's Advisory Commission on Military Training.
Subjects
Diplomatic and consular service, American.; Draft--United States.; Elections--United States.; International economic relations.; Military education--United States.; Trade regulation--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Congresses.; World War, 1939-1945.; Yachts.
Places
Belgium--Foreign relations--United States.; Belgium.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--United States.; Luxembourg--Foreign relations--United States.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-; United States--Foreign economic relations.; United States--Foreign relations--20th century.; United States--Foreign relations--Belgium.; United States--Foreign relations--Great Britain.; United States--Foreign relations--Luxembourg.; United States--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Social conditions--1945-
Occupations
Authors.; Diplomats.; Lawyers.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Joseph Edward Davies, diplomat, lawyer, and author, were deposited in the Library of Congress in 1961 by his daughters Eleanor Davies Tydings, Rahel Davies Broun, and Emlen Davies Grosjean, who converted the deposit to a gift during the years 1962-1969. Additional material was given in 1967 by Mrs. John Marshall; by the Hillwood Museum, Washington, D.C., 1993; by Joseph D. Tydings in 2007; and by the Broward County Main Library, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, in 2008.
Additional Guides
A note concerning the collection appeared in the Library's Information Bulletin, Vol. 21, No. 21 (May 21, 1962), pp. 239-240. Part I was also described in the Library of Congress Quarterly Journal of Current Acquisitions, Vol. 19, No. 3 (June 1962), p. 139.
Transfers
Audio recordings have been transferred to the Library's Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, where they are identified as part of these papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Joseph Edward Davies are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1876, Nov. 29 Born, Watertown, Wis.
1898 A.B. degree, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis.
1901 LL.B degree, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis.
1902 Married Emlen Knight
1902 1906 State's attorney, Wisconsin
1912 Chairman, western headquarters, Democratic Party campaign
1913 1915 United States commissioner of corporations
1915 1916 Chairman, Federal Trade Commission
1918 Economic adviser to President Woodrow Wilson, Versailles Peace Conference, Versailles, France
1935 Married Marjorie Post
1936 Vice chairman, Democratic National Committee
1936 1938 Ambassador to the Soviet Union
1938 1939 Ambassador to Belgium and minister to Luxembourg
1939 1941 Special assistant to Cordell Hull in charge of war emergency problems and policies
1941 Chairman, Franklin D. Roosevelt's inaugural committee Published Mission to Moscow. New York: Simon and Schuster
1942 1946 Chairman, War Relief and Control Board
1943 Special envoy with rank of ambassador to confer with Joseph Stalin
1945 Chairman, Franklin D. Roosevelt's inaugural committee Special envoy with rank of ambassador to confer with Sir Winston Churchill Special adviser with rank of ambassador, Potsdam Conference, Potsdam, Germany
1946 1947 Vice chairman, President's Committee to Study Universal Military Training
1958, May 9 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
Part I
Part I of the papers of Joseph Edward Davies (1876-1958) spans the years 1860-1957, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1936-1955. It covers American-Soviet relations and foreign affairs in general from 1936 to 1957 and is arranged in nine series: Family and Personal File, Chronological File, Memoranda, Subject File, Speeches and Writings File, Newspaper Diary, Miscellany, Addition, and Oversize.
Davies was ambassador to the Soviet Union from 1936 to 1938, and the papers are especially rich on this period and on his subsequent role as an envoy or representative for Franklin D. Roosevelt and Harry S. Truman during World War II. Of particular importance are Davies's diaries and journals and the manuscripts of two unpublished books, “In the Days of Their Power and Glory” and “Missions for Peace.” Although the papers do not contain the manuscript of Mission to Moscow, his controversial 1941 book about his years in the USSR, many documents and papers used in preparing it are included. Material for a sequel to that book, which covers a 1943 trip to Moscow during World War II by Davies, is also in the collection.
Prominent correspondents include Bernard M. Baruch, Baron Max Aitken Beaverbrook, James F. Byrnes, Sir Winston Churchill, Homer S. Cummings, Josephus Daniels, Stephen T. Early, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Edward Frederick Lindley Wood, Earl of Halifax, Felix Frankfurter, Joseph C. Grew, Andrei Andreevich Gromyko, Loy W. Henderson, Harry L. Hopkins, Cordell Hull, Arthur Krock, Oskar Lange, George C. Marshall, Marvin Hunter McIntyre, Vyacheslav Mikhaylovich Molotov, Henry Morgenthau, N. V. Novicov, Key Pittman, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Samuel I. Rosenman, Edward R. Stettinius, Harry S. Truman, Millard E. Tydings, Andrey Yanuaryevich Vyshinsky, Fred M. Vinson, Harry Morris Warner, and Sumner Welles.
Part II
Part II of the Joseph Edward Davies Papers spans the years 1893-1958, with the bulk of the material concentrated between 1912 and 1958. It is arranged in seven series: Family and Personal File, Correspondence, Subject File, Speeches and Writings File, Press File, Miscellany, and Oversize.
The Family and Personal File contains Davies's appointment books, biographical and genealogical information, correspondence between family members, estate management records, financial records, and medical records. Household papers document personal possessions and real estate. Of note are papers relating to the Sea Cloud, the private yacht of Davies and his wife, Marjorie Post, which they donated for military service during World War II. The Davies's social life is documented by club memberships, dinner lists, invitations to garden parties, and travel material.
The Correspondence series contains letters to and from Davies's friends and colleagues, particularly in the political arena. Subjects include Woodrow Wilson's 1912 presidential campaign, Davies's work on the Federal Trade Commission, his diplomatic career, and role as presidential advisor. Correspondents include Sir Winston Churchill, Stephen T. Early, Anthony Eden, Edward, Duke of Windsor, Albert Einstein, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Felix Frankfurter, Andrei Andreevich Gromyko, Warren G. Harding, W. Averell Harriman, J. Edgar Hoover, Harry L. Hopkins, Cordell Hull, Harold L. Ickes, Henry Robinson Luce, Alfred Lunt, Edward R. Murrow, Drew Pearson, Sam Rayburn, Eddie Rickenbacker, Eleanor Roosevelt, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Adlai E. Stevenson, Rafael Leónidas Trujillo Molina, Harry S. Truman, Henry A. Wallace, Sumner Welles, Wendell L. Willkie, and Woodrow Wilson.
The Subject File covers topics such as Belgium, economic and foreign relations, presidential and senatorial election campaigns, post-World War II conditions, and universal military training. The Speeches and Writings File contains correspondence, drafts, and related material pertaining to Davies's articles, books, speeches, and other writings. It includes material regarding Mission to Moscow, a film based on Davies's book. The Press File includes bulletins, newsletters, newspaper clippings, press releases, and radio broadcasts.
The Miscellany series consists of notes, photographs, and printed matter. It also includes several scrapbooks relating to Davies's family and career.
Note on the Collection
Throughout his papers Davies used the following abbreviations:
D & L or DL - Diary and Letters
M to M or MM - Mission to Moscow (1941)
M to M No. 1 or MM No. 1 - Mission to Moscow (1941)
M to M No. 2 or MM No. 2 - “Mission to Moscow” (1948)
M for P or MP - “Missions for Peace”
In the Days or Days - “In the Days of Their Power and Glory” (1955)
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in two parts composed of sixteen series:
Part I:
Family and Personal File, 1860-1941
Chronological File, 1936-1957
Memoranda, 1938-1951
Subject File, 1916-1949
Speeches and Writings File, 1899-1955
Newspaper Diary, 1941-1949
Miscellany, 1900-1956
Addition, 1940-1941
Oversize, 1899-1955
Part II:
Family and Personal File, 1902-1958
Correspondence, 1911-1958
Subject File, 1912-1956
Speeches and Writings File, 1913-1958
Press File, 1913-1957
Miscellany, 1893-1957
Oversize, 1912-1956
Container List
- Part I: Family and Personal File, 1860-1941 (Box I:1-2)
  Diary, notebook, correspondence, campaign material, financial matter, legal records, and Masonic papers.
  Arranged by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Diary, undated (Box I:1)
  - Notebook, circa 1885-1915
  - Correspondence, 1873-1897, 1918, undated
  - Campaign material, 1918-1919 See also Oversize
  - Financial matters
    - 1860-1898, 1910-1911
    - 1920-1921, 1938-1941 (Box I:2)
  - Legal records, 1860-1896
  - Masonic papers, 1877-1883
- Part I: Chronological File, 1936-1957 (Box I:3-26)
  Diaries, journals, correspondence, and related material.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1936 (Box I:3)
  - 1937
    - Feb.
      - 1-18
      - 19-28 (Box I:4)
    - Mar.-Apr.
    - May-Aug. (Box I:5)
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:6)
  - 1938 (Box I:7)
    - Jan.-Apr.
    - May-Aug. (Box I:8)
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:9)
  - 1939
    - Jan.-Mar.
    - Apr.-Dec. (Box I:10)
  - 1940-1941 (Box I:11)
  - 1942
    - Jan.-Sept.
    - Oct.-Dec. (Box I:12)
  - 1943
    - Jan.-Mar.
    - Apr.-July (Box I:13)
    - Aug.-Dec (Box I:14)
  - 1944
    - Jan.-Aug.
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:15)
  - 1945 (Box I:16)
    - Jan.-Apr.
    - May
      - 1-13
      - 14-31 (Box I:17)
    - June
    - July
      - 1-14
      - 15-24 (Box I:18)
      - 25-31 (Box I:19)
    - Aug.
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:20)
  - 1946
    - Jan.
    - Feb.-Aug. (Box I:21)
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:22)
  - 1947
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Dec. (Box I:23)
  - 1948
    - Jan.-Nov.
  - 1949-1950 (Box I:24)
  - 1951-1952 (Box I:25)
  - 1953-1957, undated (Box I:26)
- Part I: Memoranda, 1938-1951 (Box I:27-29)
  Official and unofficial memoranda.
  - 1938-1946 (Box I:27)
  - 1945-1946 (Box I:28)
  - 1946, 1951, undated (Box I:29)
- Part I: Subject File, 1916-1949 (Box I:30-92)
  Memoranda, newspaper clippings, reports, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject and therein chronologically.
  - Atomic bomb, 1945-1946 (Box I:30)
  - Churches, regarding peace and postwar, 1942-1946 (Box I:31)
  - Conferences (Box I:32)
    - Berlin, Germany, 1945-1947
    - Big Three, Moscow, USSR, and Teheran, Iran, 1943, 1945-1946
    - Council of Foreign Ministers, London, England (Box I:33)
      - 1945
      - 1946
        - Jan.-Apr.
        - July-Dec. (Box I:34)
      - 1947
    - Dumbarton Oaks, Washington, D.C., 1944-1945 (Box I:35)
    - General, 1945-1948
    - London-Potsdam, 1945, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box I:36)
    - Paris, France, 1946
    - Potsdam, Germany, 1945 (Box I:37)
    - San Francisco, Calif. (Box I:38)
      - 1945
        - Feb.-June
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box I:39)
      - 1946
        - Jan.-Feb.
        - Mar.
          - 1-28
          - 29-31 (Box I:40)
        - Apr.-Oct.
        - Nov.
          - 1-15
          - 16-30 (Box I:41)
        - Dec.
      - 1947 (Box I:42)
    - Yalta, USSR, 1945
  - Cooperation: peace, war, and postwar (Box I:43)
    - Air power, aviation, and air rights, 1943-1947
    - General
      - 1939-1942
      - 1943
        - Jan.-Aug.
        - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:44)
      - 1944
        - Jan.-Sept.
        - Oct.-Dec. (Box I:45)
      - 1945-1948
  - Countries (Box I:46)
    - Austria, 1944-1948
    - Balkans
      - Albania and Greece
        - 1944-1945
        - 1946
          - Jan.-Nov.
          - Dec.
            - 1-8
            - 12-31 (Box I:47)
        - 1947
      - Bulgaria, Hungary, Romania, and Turkey, 1945-1947
      - General, 1945-1947 (Box I:48)
      - Yugoslavia
        - 1943-1945
        - 1946
          - Jan.-July
          - Aug.
            - 1-24
            - 25-31 (Box I:49)
          - Sept.-Dec.
        - 1947-1949
    - Belgium, Denmark, Luxembourg, and Netherlands, 1940-1948
    - China, 1935-1949, (7 folders); (3 folders) (Box I:50, Box I:51)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1943-1948
    - Finland, 1940-1949 (Box I:52)
    - France, 1942-1948, (5 folders); (3 folders) (Box I:53)
    - General, A-Z, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box I:54)
    - Germany, 1940-1947, (3 folders); (8 folders) (Box I:55, Box I:56)
    - Great Britain and the Commonwealth (Box I:57)
      - 1938-1944
      - 1945
        - Jan.-June
        - July
          - 1-29
          - 30-31 (Box I:58)
        - Aug.-Dec.
      - 1946
      - 1947 (Box I:59)
    - Italy, 1943-1946 (Box I:60)
    - Japan and Korea, 1945-1948, (6 folders); (2 folder) (Box I:61)
    - Near East and Middle East, 1943-1948, (12 folders); (3 folders) (Box I:62)
    - Poland
      - Miscellany
        - 1943
        - 1944
          - Jan.-Apr.
          - May
            - 1-20
            - 28-31 (Box I:63)
        - 1945
          - Jan.-June
          - July
            - 1-15
            - 16-31 (Box I:64)
        - 1946-1947
      - Newspaper clippings and diaries, 1943-1945
      - White Book headings, 1935-1939, undated
    - Russia (Box I:65)
      - Diplomacy
        - 1943
        - 1944
          - Jan.-Oct.
          - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:66)
        - 1945-1946
        - 1947-1948 (Box I:67)
      - Economic Bulletin on the Soviet Union and related publications, 1944-1947
      - Freeman, Joseph, Stabilization of the Russian Revolution, 1942
      - Gallup poll regarding Russia, 1944
      - Miscellany
        - Typescripts, 1938-1946, (5 folders); (6 folders); (7 folders); (2 folders) (Box I:68, Box I:69, Box I:70)
        - Newspaper clippings and other material
          - 1941-1945
          - 1946
            - Jan.-Mar.
            - Apr.-Dec. (Box I:71)
      - Religion, 1942-1948
      - Russia Defends the Motherland (Soviet film), 1943
      - Russian campaign
        - 1942-1943
        - 1944-1945 (Box I:72)
      - Soviet-German relations, 1938-1939, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box I:73)
      - Soviet-Polish relations, 1941-1944
      - Stalin, Joseph, 1941-1946
      - Ukraine, Belarus, and Baltic states, 1943-1944 (Box I:74)
    - United States
      - Foreign policy
        - 1943-1944
        - 1945
          - Jan.
            - 1-21
            - 26-31 (Box I:75)
          - Feb.-Dec.
        - 1946
          - Jan.-Oct.
          - Nov.
            - 2
            - 3-30 (Box I:76)
          - Dec.
        - 1947
      - "Making Haste Slowly and the Post War World," 1943
      - Miscellany
        - 1943
          - Feb.-Sept.
          - Oct.
            - 1-3
            - 10-31 (Box I:77)
        - 1944-1948
      - Presidential campaign, 1944 (Box I:78)
  - Economic cartels, 1916-1945 (Box I:79)
  - Economic trade
    - 1941-1943
    - 1944
      - May
        - 1-3
        - 7-31 (Box I:80)
    - 1945-1948
  - Legacies of suspicion (Box I:81)
    - 1936-1943
    - 1944
      - Sept.
        - 1-26
        - 28-30 (Box I:82)
    - 1945
      - Jan.-July
      - Aug.
        - 1-24
        - 25-31 (Box I:83)
      - Sept.-Dec.
    - 1946
      - Jan.-Aug.
      - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:84)
    - 1947
  - Lend-lease operations and Allied aid to Russia, 1943-1947 (Box I:85)
  - Monetary
    - 1944-1945
    - 1946
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-Dec. (Box I:86)
    - 1947-1948
  - Relief and rehabilitation, 1943-1947
  - Universal military training, president's advisory commission, 1946-1947, (6 folders); (10 folders); (2 folders) (Box I:87, Box I:88, Box I:89)
  - War
    - Miscellany
      - 1939-1944
      - 1945
        - Jan.-Apr.
        - May-Dec. (Box I:90)
      - 1946-1948
    - Second front, 1942-1943
  - War criminals
    - German trials, background material, 1945, undated
    - Miscellany, 1943-1948, (9 folders); (10 folders) (Box I:91, Box I:92)
- Part I: Speeches and Writings File, 1899-1955 (Box I:93-113)
  Drafts of articles, books, and speeches with related research material, correspondence, printed matter, photographs, contracts, and miscellany.
  Articles and speeches are arranged chronologically. Books are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Articles (Box I:93)
    - 1917, 1938-1943
    - 1943-1946, undated (Box I:94)
  - Books (Box I:95)
    - “In the Days of Their Power and Glory”
      - Contracts and related material, 1955-1959
      - Correspondence
        - Carter, John Franklin, 1955-1959
        - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1944-1957
      - Memoranda and information for editors, 1953-1954
      - Miscellany, 1955-1956, undated
      - Outlines, indexes, and tables of content, 1953-1954, undated (Box I:96)
      - Photographs, 1899-1955, undated See also Oversize
      - Typescripts and related material
        - First carbon, circa 1954
          - Pages 1-469
          - Pages 470-1083 (Box I:97)
        - Second carbon, pages 1-1082, 1954-1956, undated (Box I:98)
        - Miscellany (Box I:99)
          - 1954-1955
            - Set I, pages 1-629
            - Set II
              - Pages 1-248
              - Pages 250-629 (Box I:100)
              - Appendix
            - Set III
              - Pages 1-121
              - Pages 122-629 (Box I:101)
          - 1957
    - “Inaugural Résumé,” 1941
    - Mission to Moscow
      - 1941
        - Film
          - Scripts, treatments, and related material, 1942-1943, undated
          - Working papers, 1939-1943, undated (Box I:102)
        - Promotional material
          - 1941-1944
          - Undated (Box I:103)
      - 1948
        - Background material, 1941-1943 See also Oversize
        - Correspondence, 1943, undated (Box I:104)
        - Film, 1943-1944
        - Introductions and other textual material, 1948
        - Lange, Oskar, 1945
        - Miscellany, 1941-1945, undated
        - Newspapers, newspaper clippings, articles, and press releases, 1943
    - “Missions for Peace”
      - Background material and photographs, 1955, undated
      - Typescript fragments, 1955, undated (Box I:105)
      - Typescripts
        - 1950
        - 1953-1954
          - Set I
            - Pages 1-90
            - Pages 92-879 (Box I:106)
            - Pages 897-1607 (Box I:107)
          - Set II
            - Vol. 1
            - Vols. 2-6 (Box I:108)
            - Vol. 7 (Box I:109)
        - 1955
          - Set I
            - Pages 1-154
            - Pages 155-349 (Box I:110)
          - Set II
            - Pages 1-496
        - circa 1955
    - “Notes on Potsdam Conference,” 1945 (Box I:111)
    - “Rise and Fall of Deterioration, 1776,” 1949, 1950
  - Speeches (Box I:112)
    - 1915, 1936-1941
    - 1942-1946, 1955, undated (Box I:113)
- Part I: Newspaper Diary, 1941-1949 (Box I:114-146)
  Newspaper clippings.
  - 1941-1942 (Box I:114)
  - 1943
    - Jan.-Apr.
    - May-Oct. (Box I:115)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:116)
  - 1944
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-June (Box I:117)
    - July-Oct. (Box I:118)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:119)
  - 1945
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-May (Box I:120)
    - June-Aug. (Box I:121)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box I:122)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:123)
  - 1946 (Box I:124)
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Apr. (Box I:125)
    - May-June (Box I:126)
    - July-Aug. (Box I:127)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box I:128)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:129)
  - 1947 (Box I:130)
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Apr. (Box I:131)
    - May-June (Box I:132)
    - July-Aug. (Box I:133)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box I:134)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:135)
  - 1948 (Box I:136)
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Apr. (Box I:137)
    - May-June (Box I:138)
    - July-Sept. (Box I:139)